A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1953
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1953
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.631
This collection consists of 15,600 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred. Date unknown.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
There are also two small architectural drawings of Parking at the Law School and Plan of a Paved Access Road at the Architecture School.
Contents List
- General Files, 1954
  - "A" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 1)
  - Academic Organization 1953 (Box 1)
  - Air Forces 1953 (Box 1)
  - Alumni Office 1953 (Box 1)
  - American Association of University Professors 1953 (Box 1)
  - American Council on Education 1953 (Box 1)
  - American Institute of Pacific Relations 1953 (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "A" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "B" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "C" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "D" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "E" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "F" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "G" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "H" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "I" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "J" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "K" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "L" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "M" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "N" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "O" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "P" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "Q" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "R" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "S" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "T" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "U" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "V" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "W" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Applications for Positions - "X -Y - Z" 1953 (Box 2)
  - Architecture 1953 (Box 3)
  - Army - General 1953 (Box 3)
  - Army -Judge Advocate General's (J.A.G.) School 1953 (Box 3)
  - Army Medical Corps 1953 (Box 3)
  - Art 1953 (Box 3)
  - Art Commission 1953 (Box 3)
  - Association of American Colleges 1953 (Box 3)
  - Association of American Universities 1953 (Box 3)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1953 (Box 3)
  - Association of Land-Grant Colleges 1953 (Box 3)
  - Astronomy 1953 (Box 3)
  - Athletics: January - June 1953 (Box 4)
  - Athletics: July - December 1953 (Box 4)
  - Athletics - NCAA 1953 (Box 4)
  - Athletics - Commonwealth Day 1953 (Box 4)
  - Atlantic Union (folder empty) 1953 (Box 4)
  - Attorney General 1953 (Box 4)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts 1953 (Box 4)
  - "Ba - Bl" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 5)
  - "Bm - Bz" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 5)
  - Biology 1953 (Box 5)
  - Bursar: January - June 1953 (Box 6)
  - Bursar: July - December 1953 (Box 6)
  - Bibliographical Society 1953 (Box 6)
  - Biology - Mountain Lake 1953 (Box 6)
  - Blandy Farm 1953 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Cemetery 1953 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Chemistry 1953 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Electricity 1953 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Roads 1953 (Box 6)
  - Buildings and Grounds - General 1953 (Box 7)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Academic Building 1953 (Box 7)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Architects and Engineers 1953 (Box 7)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Contracts 1953 (Box 7)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Life Science Building 1953 (Box 7)
  - Building Program - General 1953 (Box 7)
  - Building Program - Medical Buildings 1953 (Box 8)
  - Building Program - Men's Dormitories 1953 (Box 8)
  - Building Program - Natural Resources (folder empty) 1953 (Box 8)
  - Building Program - Naval Armory 1953 (Box 8)
  - Building Program - Physics Building 1953 (Box 8)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Power Plant and Heating Mains 1953 (Box 9)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Student Activities Building 1953 (Box 9)
  - Buildings and Grounds - Women's Dormitory (folder empty) 1953 (Box 9)
  - Budget Exhibits 1953 (Box 9)
  - Byrd, Senator Harry F. 1953 (Box 9)
  - "Ca - Ck" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 9)
  - "Cl - Cz" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 9)
  - Carnegie Corporation 1953 (Box 10)
  - Catalogues 1953 (Box 10)
  - Cavalier Daily 1953 (Box 10)
  - Chemistry - John Lee Pratt Trace Analysis Laboratory 1953 (Box 10)
  - Chemistry 1953 (Box 10)
  - College of Arts and Sciences 1953 (Box 10)
  - Civilian Defense 1953 (Box 10)
  - Classics 1953 (Box 10)
  - Clippings 1953 (Box 10)
  - Committee - New Material 1953 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Academic Legislation 1953 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Administrative Policy Committee of the Hospital 1953 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Admissions (College) 1953 (Box 10)
  - Committee - Algernon Sydney Sullivan Award 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Art Museum 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Athletics 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Blandy Farm 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Board 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Calendar 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Catalogue 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Cemetery 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Chapel 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Chaperones (folder empty) 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Free Asia 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Contractual Relations 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Extension 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Fellowship Awards 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Final Comprehensive Exams in the College 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Fire Protection 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Graduate School of Business 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Honors Courses 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Institute of Public Affairs Advisory 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Institute for Research in the Social Sciences 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Lectures 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Lectures - Page-Barbour and J. W. Richard 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Library 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Lower Division 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Medical Board of the Hospital 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Mountain Lake Biological Station 1953 (Box 11)
  - Committee - Nursing School Advisory 1953 (Box 12)
  - Committee - Patents 1953 (Box 12)
  - Committee - Public Occasions 1953 (Box 12)
  - Committee - Research 1953 (Box 12)
  - Committee - Rhodes Scholarship 1953 (Box 12)
  - Committee - Rules and Courses (College) 1953 (Box 12)
  - Committee - Rules and Courses (Graduate) 1953 (Box 12)
  - Committee - Rules and Courses (Medical) 1953 (Box 12)
  - Committee - Rushton Seminars (folder empty) 1953 (Box 12)
  - Committee - Schedule and Classroom Assignments 1953 (Box 12)
  - Committee - Scholarship, Loans, and Employment 1953 (Box 12)
  - Committee - Science 1953 (Box 12)
  - Committee - Summer Session 1953 (Box 12)
  - Committee - Student Union 1953 (Box 12)
  - Committee - Summer Session Degrees 1953 (Box 12)
  - Committee - Summer Session Degrees (Graduate) 1953 (Box 12)
  - Committee - Teacher Placement 1953 (Box 12)
  - Committee - Tree 1953 (Box 12)
  - Committee - Virginia Quarterly Review 1953 (Box 12)
  - Committee - Virginia Status of University Students 1953 (Box 12)
  - Compulsory Education 1953 (Box 12)
  - Comptroller (State) 1953 (Box 12)
  - Council of Southern Universities 1953 (Box 12)
  - Council of State Government 1953 (Box 12)
  - "D" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 12)
  - Davis, William Holmes 1953 (Box 12)
  - Development Fund 1953 (Box 13)
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 13)
  - Economics: January - June 1953 (Box 14)
  - Economics: July - December 1953 (Box 14)
  - Education 1953 (Box 15)
  - Alumni Board of Trustees Endowment Fund 1953 (Box 15)
  - Alumni Board of Trustees Endowment Fund - Contingent Fund 1953 (Box 15)
  - English 1953 (Box 16)
  - Engineering 1953 (Box 16)
  - Engineering Open House 1953 (Box 16)
  - Extension Division 1953 (Box 16)
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 17)
  - Faculty 1953 (Box 17)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 17)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Bayly-Tiffany 1953 (Box 17)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Ford Foundation 1953 (Box 18)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Fulbright 1953 (Box 18)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships - Rhodes 1953 (Box 18)
  - Finals 1953 (Box 18)
  - Food Services 1953 (Box 18)
  - Foreign Affairs 1953 (Box 18)
  - Forestry 1953 (Box 18)
  - Founder's Day 1953 (Box 18)
  - Fraternities 1953 (Box 18)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 19)
  - Garden Club 1953 (Box 19)
  - General Education Board 1953 (Box 19)
  - Geography 1953 (Box 19)
  - Geology 1953 (Box 19)
  - Germanic Languages and Russian 1953 (Box 19)
  - Gifts and Grants - Development Fund 1953 (Box 19)
  - Gifts and Grants - Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 19)
  - Governor's Office 1953 (Box 20)
  - Governor's Office - Approvals of Gifts and Grants 1953 (Box 20)
  - Graduate 1953 (Box 20)
  - "Ha - He" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 20)
  - "Hi - Hz" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 20)
  - Highway Department (State) 1953 (Box 21)
  - Hildreth, W. S. 1953 (Box 21)
  - History 1953 (Box 21)
  - Honors Courses (folder empty) 1953 (Box 21)
  - Honor System 1953 (Box 21)
  - Hospital: January - June 1953 (Box 21)
  - Hospital: July - December 1953 (Box 21)
  - Hospital - Medical Board 1953 (Box 21)
  - Hospital - Monthly Statistical Reports 1953 (Box 21)
  - Hospital - Blue Cross matters 1953 (Box 21)
  - Housing 1953 (Box 22)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 22)
  - Institute of International Education 1953 (Box 22)
  - Institute of Public Affairs 1953 (Box 22)
  - Insurance 1953 (Box 22)
  - International Association of Universities 1953 (Box 22)
  - Invitations - "A" 1953 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "B" 1953 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "C" 1953 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "D" 1953 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "E" 1953 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "F" 1953 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "G" 1953 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "H" 1953 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "I" 1953 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "J" 1953 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "K" 1953 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "L" 1953 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "M" 1953 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "N" 1953 (Box 23)
  - Invitations - "O" 1953 (Box 24)
  - Invitations - "P" 1953 (Box 24)
  - Invitations - "Q" 1953 (Box 24)
  - Invitations - "R" 1953 (Box 24)
  - Invitations - "S" 1953 (Box 24)
  - Invitations - "T" 1953 (Box 24)
  - Invitations - "U" 1953 (Box 24)
  - Invitations - "V" 1953 (Box 24)
  - Invitations - "W" 1953 (Box 24)
  - Invitations - "X - Y - Z" 1953 (Box 24)
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 25)
  - Jamestown Exposition 1953 (Box 25)
  - Japan Christian University 1953 (Box 25)
  - Jefferson - Thomas, Memorial Foundation 1953 (Box 25)
  - Jefferson-Jackson Day Dinner 1953 (Box 25)
  - Judge Advocate General's School (folder empty) 1953 (Box 25)
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 25)
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 26)
  - Law School 1953 (Box 26)
  - Lectures - General 1953 (Box 26)
  - Lectures - Page-Barbour 1953 (Box 26)
  - Lectures - Richard 1953 (Box 26)
  - Legal Matters 1953 (Box 26)
  - Legislative Program 1953 (Box 26)
  - McGregor Library 1953 (Box 26)
  - Loan Funds (folder empty) 1953 (Box 26)
  - Lower Division 1953 (Box 26)
  - Library 1953 (Box 26)
  - Manual for First-Year Advisors at the University of Virginia, by Raymond C. Bice, Jr. 1953 (Box 26)
  - "Ma - Me" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 27)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 27)
  - "MI - Mz" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 27)
  - McIntire Fund 1953 (Box 27)
  - Madison Hall 1953 (Box 27)
  - Marine Corps (folder empty) 1953 (Box 27)
  - Mary Washington College 1953 (Box 28)
  - Mary Washington College - Biennial Budget 1953 (Box 28)
  - Mary Washington College - Dockets 1953 (Box 28)
  - Mathematics 1953 (Box 28)
  - Medical School 1953 (Box 28)
  - Music 1953 (Box 28)
  - N" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 29)
  - National Association of State Universities 1953 (Box 29)
  - National Commission on Accrediting 1953 (Box 29)
  - National Education Association 1953 (Box 29)
  - National Science Foundation 1953 (Box 29)
  - Navy - General 1953 (Box 29)
  - Navy - ROTC 1953 (Box 29)
  - Newcomb, J. L. 1953 (Box 29)
  - Nursing School 1953 (Box 29)
  - Nursing Education 1953 (Box 29)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 30)
  - Oak Ridge 1953 (Box 30)
  - "Pa - Pe" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 30)
  - "Pf - Pz" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 30)
  - Patents (folder empty) 1953 (Box 30)
  - Personnel (State) 1953 (Box 30)
  - Personnel and Placement (Students) 1953 (Box 30)
  - Philosophy 1953 (Box 30)
  - Photographs 1953 (Box 30)
  - Physical Education 1953 (Box 30)
  - Physics 1953 (Box 30)
  - Political Science 1953 (Box 30)
  - Printing 1953 (Box 30)
  - President's Council 1953 (Box 30)
  - Psychology 1953 (Box 30)
  - Publications and Clippings 1953 (Box 30)
  - Purchase and Printing (State Office) 1953 (Box 30)
  - Purchase Office (University) 1953 (Box 30)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 31)
  - Questionnaires 1953 (Box 31)
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 31)
  - Radio 1953 (Box 31)
  - Raven Society 1953 (Box 31)
  - Recommendations 1953 (Box 31)
  - Regional Education 1953 (Box 32)
  - Registrar 1953 (Box 32)
  - Religion 1953 (Box 32)
  - Requisitions 1953 (Box 32)
  - Research - Bureau Population and Economic 1953 (Box 32)
  - Research - General 1953 (Box 32)
  - Research - Institute for Research in Social Sciences 1953 (Box 32)
  - Research - National Research Council 1953 (Box 32)
  - Richmond Area University Center 1953 (Box 32)
  - Romance Languages 1953 (Box 32)
  - Rural Social Economics 1953 (Box 32)
  - "Sa - Sl" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 33)
  - "Sm - Sz" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 33)
  - Salaries 1953 (Box 33)
  - Segregation 1953 (Box 33)
  - Selective Service (folder empty) 1953 (Box 33)
  - Senate (University) 1953 (Box 34)
  - Sigma Xi 1953 (Box 34)
  - Social Security (folder empty) 1953 (Box 34)
  - Sociology (folder empty) 1953 (Box 34)
  - Southern Association of Science and Industry 1953 (Box 34)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools 1953 (Box 34)
  - Southern University Conference 1953 (Box 34)
  - Speech and Drama 1953 (Box 34)
  - Speeches and Articles 1953 (Box 34)
  - State Board of Education 1953 (Box 34)
  - State Board of Health (folder empty) 1953 (Box 34)
  - State University Association 1953 (Box 35)
  - Statistics 1953 (Box 35)
  - Student Aid Office 1953 (Box 35)
  - Student Affairs Office 1953 (Box 35)
  - Student Health Department 1953 (Box 35)
  - Sullivan Awards 1953 (Box 35)
  - Summer Session 1953 (Box 35)
  - Surplus Property 1953 (Box 35)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 36)
  - Television 1953 (Box 36)
  - Travel 1953 (Box 36)
  - Treasurer of Virginia 1953 (Box 36)
  - Treasury Department (U. S.) 1953 (Box 36)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 37)
  - United Nations 1953 (Box 37)
  - University Houses - Applications (folder empty) 1953 (Box 37)
  - U. S. Office of Education 1953 (Box 37)
  - University News Service 1953 (Box 37)
  - University Press 1953 (Box 37)
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 37)
  - Veterans 1953 (Box 37)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1953 (Box 37)
  - Virginia Advisory Legislative Council 1953 (Box 37)
  - Virginia Education Association 1953 (Box 37)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1953 (Box 37)
  - Virginia State Chamber of Commerce 1953 (Box 37)
  - Visitors - Dockets 1953 (Box 38)
  - Visitors - General Correspondence 1953 (Box 38)
  - Visitors - Mr. Black 1953 (Box 38)
  - Visitors - Judge Barksdale 1953 (Box 38)
  - Visitors - Mr. Carrington 1953 (Box 39)
  - Visitors - Mr. Coxe 1953 (Box 39)
  - Visitors - Dr. Emmett 1953 (Box 39)
  - Visitors - Mr. Gravatt 1953 (Box 39)
  - Visitors - Mr. Howard 1953 (Box 39)
  - Visitors - Mr. Mears 1953 (Box 39)
  - Visitors - Mrs. H. M. Smith 1953 (Box 39)
  - Visitors - Mr. Howard Smith 1953 (Box 39)
  - Visitors - Mr. Talbott 1953 (Box 39)
  - Visitors - Mrs. Wailes 1953 (Box 39)
  - Visitors - Ms. Wheeler 1953 (Box 39)
  - "Wa - Wh" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 40)
  - "Wi - Wz" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 40)
  - Wilson (Woodrow) Birthplace Foundation 1953 (Box 40)
  - Women, Dean of 1953 (Box 40)
  - "X - Y - Z" Miscellaneous 1953 (Box 40)